Guide to the Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 6. Public Relations and Media Files, 1972-2010 TJU.2010.01.06
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Press Office, 1981-2005; IV.
  - Press Releases, 1981-2005; 1.
    - 1989 (Box 1223, Folder 2)
      - Senator Specter endorses two republican candidates for judge at news conference at federal building in Philadelphia, April 21, 1989; 36.
      - Senator Specter announces more than $1.75 million in FAA grants, April 21, 1989; 37.
      - Senator Specter announces $5.6 million federal grant to establish research center for the study of drug abuse vulnerability in Pittsburgh, May 2, 1989; 38.
      - Senator Specter's budget amendment to transfer $100 million to provide more prison cells and to add more funding for BATF is adopted by the Senate, May 3, 1989; 39.
      - Senator Specter introduces legislation to provide $100 million to provide health care for children with AIDS, May 3, 1989; 40.
      - Senator Specter says Congress, contrary to DOD's budget, will want to continue Boeing Vertol's V-22 program; asks DOD to keep program until Congress decides, May 4, 1989; 41.
      - Senator Specter asks DEA to provide an agent to help in fighting drug trafficking in Scranton-Wilkes Barre and New Castle areas, May 9, 1989; 42.
      - Senator Specter announces that Audubon home in Montgomery County has been designated a National Historic Landmark, May 9, 1989; 43.
      - Senator Specter introduces resolution to commend neighborhood crime watch groups and to designate August 8, 1989, as "Crime Watch Day", May 17, 1989; 44.
      - Senator Specter disputes DOD claims regarding cost of V-22 Osprey; asks for hearing on costs before Senate Defense Subcommittee, May 17, 1989; 45.
      - Montford Point Marine Association deserves national recognition, May 18, 1989; 46.
      - U.S. Senators Heinz and Specter make recommendations for appointments to U.S. District Courts, U.S. Attorney, and U.S. Marshal's office, May 18, 1989; 47.
      - Senator Specter to push hard for funding for Philadelphia projects in fiscal year 1990 budget, June, 1989; 48.
      - Senator Specter to push hard for Erie projects in fiscal year 1990 budget, June 5, 1989; 49.
      - Specter to push hard for funding for western Pennsylvania projects in fiscal year 1990, June 6, 1989; 50.
      - Senator Specter to push hard for funding for mine health and safety, and mine reclamation funds, June 6, 1989; 51.
      - Senator Specter announces $10.6 million federal grant to Pennsylvania to regulate surface effects of coal mining, June 7, 1989; 52.
      - Senator Specter announces $1.6 million in supplemental budget for Urban Education Foundation in Philadelphia, June 8, 1989; 53.
      - Senator Specter requests "thorough explanation" from Pittsburgh and Lebanon VA medical centers cited for high mortality rates in official report, June 16, 1989; 54.
      - Senators Specter, Dole, and Thurmond introduce Bush Administration's comprehensive anti-crime legislation, June 22, 1989; 55.
      - Senator Specter finally gets remainder of federal funding promised to the Urban Education Foundation at 46th and Market Streets, June 23, 1989; 56.
      - Senator Specter urges EPA and Coast Guard "to make every effort" to mitigate environmental damage of June 24 Delaware River oil spill, June 26, 1989; 57.
      - Senator Specter urges establishment of satellite federal court in Lewisburg, June 26, 1989; 58.
      - Senators Specter and Heinz, and Congressman Gekas ask Jordan's King Hussein to intervene in child abduction case, June 27, 1989; 59.
      - Senator Specter announces more than $2.6 million in grants for Pennsylvania housing projects, June 26, 1989; 60.
      - Senator Specter announces $30.3 million in UTMA grants to state transit units, June 28, 1989; 61.
      - Senator Specter comments on U.S. Supreme Court decision on abortion issue, July 3, 1989; 62.
      - Senator Specter urges Amtrak to locate its new facility for passenger car rehabilitation in the Mon Valley, July 6, 1989; 63.
      - Secretary of Veterans Affairs Edward Derwinski joins Senator Specter on cable call-in program, July 10, 1989; 64.
      - Senators Specter and Sasser introduce legislation that would provide free college education in return for police service, July 12, 1989; 65.
      - Senator Specter's amendment to the immigration bill that would allow more business-sponsored immigration was passed today by the U.S. Senate, July 13, 1989; 66.
      - Senators Specter and Heinz announce reappointment of Donald Unangst as Administrator of the Agriculture Stabilization and Conservation Service, July 14, 1989; 67.
      - Senator Specter reintroduces legislation that would create an independent Inspector General for the FBI, July 18, 1989; 68.
      - Senator Specter introduces amendment to foreign relations bill that would impose the death penalty on terrorists who murder U.S. citizens abroad, July 19, 1989; 69.
      - Senator Specter announces funding by Senate subcommittee for PA water projects, July 20, 1989; 70.
      - Senate accepts two anti-terrorism proposals by Senator Specter: defers vote on third until after the August recess, July 21, 1989; 71.
      - Senator Specter pushes international strike force and court in speech here at dedication of cruiser, Gettysburg, July 22, 1989; 72.
      - Senator Specter announces that Tom Larson, for PA Transportation Secretary, confirmed by Senate as new Federal Highway Administrator, July 25, 1989; 73.
      - Senator Specter announces subcommittee action to provide $250,000 for the National Constitutional Center in Philadelphia, July 25, 1989; 74.
      - Senator Specter announces committee action to provide funding for two historic projects at Gettysburg, July 25, 1989; 75.
      - Senator Specter's response to Bush Administration's decision to extend steel voluntary restraint agreements, July 25, 1989; 76.
      - Senator Specter announces Senate action to provide funding for important western Pennsylvania water projects, July 28, 1989; 77.
      - Senator Specter calls on DOD and CIA to report on efforts made and resources needed to free American hostages in Lebanon, August 2, 1989; 78.
      - Senator Specter announces federal grant for north Philadelphia recycling center, August 2, 1989; 79.
      - Senator Specter urges Senate colleagues to restore funding for the V-22 Osprey program; amendment passes in a voice vote, August 2, 1989; 80.
      - Senator Specter announces that Easton, PA, will be restored to the Lehigh Valley's metropolitan statistical area title, August 4, 1989; 81.
      - Senator Specter objects to Air Force plan to use south central PA as target range for bombing practice: urges abandonment of this plan, August 8, 1989; 82.
      - Senator Specter announces appointment of Wilkes-Barre women as regional for ACTION, the federal domestic volunteer agency, August 8, 1989; 83.
      - Senator Specter considering interstate compact to address region's trash disposal problems, August 14, 1989; 84.
      - Senator Specter pleased that Air Force to abandon plan for flights over central Pennsylvania wildlife and state park areas, August 16, 1989; 85.
      - Senator Specter announces $10 million for Pittsburgh airport, August 18, 1989; 86.
      - Senator Specter announces $15 million for bell helicopter, August 23, 1989; 87.
      - Senator Specter steps up efforts to form multinational force to fight international drug traffickers, August 24, 1989; 88.
      - Senator Specter announces $6 million for trade adjustment assistance, August 24, 1989; 89.
      - Penn State chosen as one of 17 universities for space grant, August 31, 1989; 90.
      - Senator Specter announces $50 million DOE award to Westinghouse, Monroeville for development of new design nuclear reactor plant, September 5, 1989; 91.
      - Statement of Senator Specter on President Bush's war on drugs national message, September 5, 1989; 92.
      - Senator Specter announces that Drug Czar William Bennett to come to Philadelphia on Monday, September 18, for a first-hand look at city's drug problem, September 8, 1989; 93.
      - U.S. Senators Specter and Heinz to visit drug rehabilitation center in Philadelphia on Monday; Drug czar Bennett visit cancelled, September 18, 1989; 94.
      - Senator Specter announces Lock Haven to get $7.6 million in fiscal year 1990 for flood control project, September 7, 1989; 95.
      - Senator Specter announces that Philadelphia drug task force to get continued federal funding, September 12, 1989; 96.
      - Senators Specter and Heinz introduce legislation that would enlarge the Gettysburg National Military Park by almost 1,900 acres, September 12, 1989; 97.
      - Senator Specter again proposes Office of Minority Health within the Department of Health and Human Services, September 12, 1989; 98.
      - Senator Specter announces approval of $10 million appropriation by the Senate for construction of a new warehouse at the PSNY, September 14, 1989; 99.
      - Senator Specter announces federal funding increases for health and educational services in nation's rural areas, September 14, 1989; 100.
      - Senator Specter announces funding increases for health and refugee programs, September 14, 1989; 101.
      - Senator Specter asks Navy for decommissioned naval vessel for port of Erie to use as a tourist attraction, September 20, 1989; 102.
      - Senators Specter and Heinz introduce legislation to transfer the colonial courthouse in York, PA, to the U.S. National Park Service, September 20, 1989; 103.
      - Senator Specter announces $3.3 million in FAA discretionary grants for three central Pennsylvania airports, September 21, 1989; 104.
      - Specter amendment provides additional $50 million in federal grants for low-income home heating, September 21, 1989; 105.
      - Senator Specter today called on all Americans to become personally involved in the national war against drugs, September 21, 1989; 106.
      - Senator Specter asks HUD Secretary Jack Kemp for federal funding to assist in development of Erie's bayfront area, September 22, 1989; 107.
      - Senator Specter urges EPA to grant request for an environmental impact study of landfills in northeastern Pennsylvania, September 22, 1989; 108.
      - Senator Specter to bring anti-drug message to students in three central Pennsylvania schools on Monday, September 25, September 25, 1989; 109.
      - Senator Specter urges Governor Casey to ensure local financing for federally-funded flood control projects at Lock Haven and Tamaqua, September 26, 1989; 110.
      - Senator Specter urges subcommittee to name Greene County for federal funds to construct a prison, September 26, 1989; 111.
      - Senator Specter announces Air Force contract for $77 million for General Electric in Philadelphia, September 27, 1989; 112.
      - Senator Specter announces that transportation bill, passed today by the Senate, will benefit number of Pennsylvania projects, September 27, 1989; 113.
      - Senate passes Senator Specter's amendment to fund U.S. forces for participation in a multinational ant-narcotics strike force, September 28, 1989; 114.
      - Senator Specter announces that $12 million in funding restored for Steamtown National Historic Park, September 28, 1989; 115.
      - Senator Specter announces federal funding for a number of historic and environmental Pennsylvania projects, September 28, 1989; 116.
      - Senator Specter announces HUD guaranteed loans for housing for elderly and handicapped in Pennsylvania, September 29, 1989; 117.
      - Senator Specter announces $13.4 million grant to PA to reclaim abandoned mines, September 29, 1989; 118.
      - "Call Senator Specter" to focus on the impact of drugs on America's children, October 2, 1989; 119.
      - Senators Specter and Heinz and Congressman Goodling want Gettysburg Address to remain at Gettysburg National Military Park, October 3, 1989; 120.
      - Senator Specter urges expeditious relocation of radar antenna at Scranton-Wilkes Barre airport in Avoca, PA, October 4, 1989; 121.
      - Senator Specter announces increases in federal funding for mine safety and for the processing of appeals claims in black lung disease cases, October 5, 1989; 122.
      - Senator Specter announces 2.8 million HUD grant to Washington Square Associates for 100 units of housing in Harrisburg, October 6, 1989; 123.
      - Senator Specter announces $9.6 million U.S. Army contract for Exide Corp., Reading, PA, for manufacture of batteries, October 6, 1989; 124.
      - Grant award to Philadelphia for "putting prisoners to work", October 13, 1989; 125.
      - Senator Specter says state to get $15 million to build Veterans Administration nursing home in Scranton, PA, October 18, 1989; 126.
      - Senator Specter proposes specific reforms to remedy current evils in corporate takeovers, October 25, 1989; 127.
      - Senate passes Senator Specter bill that would impose death penalty on terrorists who murder U.S. citizens overseas, October 26, 1989; 128.
      - Senators Specter and Heinz and 25 other Senators ask Defense Department for "fair and thorough" cost effectiveness analysis of Boeing Vertol's V-22 Osprey, October 27, 1989; 129.
      - Senator Specter calls for death penalty for major drug traffickers, November 1, 1989; 130.
      - Senate passes Senator Specter's bill to create independent, statutory IG for CIA, November 7, 1989; 131.
      - Senator Specter announces that federal prison system to accept 400 more PA inmates as a result of the Camp Hill prison riots, November 9, 1989; 132.
      - Senator Specter announces $301 million in DOD funding for Boeing's V-22 Osprey program in fiscal year 1990 budget, November 9, 1989; 133.
      - Senator Specter urges the State Department to stress U.S. commitment to protecting innocent lives and promoting human rights in El Salvador, November 17, 1989; 134.
      - Senator Specter seeks speedy confirmation hearing for Lancaster Judge Robert Buckwalter to the U.S. District Court for Eastern District of PA, November 20, 1989; 135.
      - Senator Arlen Specter requests investigation into Conrail derailment which caused evacuation of area residents, November 20, 1989; 136.
      - Senator Specter introduces legislation to require colleges to report all campus crime to the FBI and to students and college employees, November 20, 1989; 137.
      - Senator Specter urges Bush Administration to sell surplus U.S. coal to Poland and Eastern Europe to relieve their shortages and boost U.S. coal industry, November 20, 1989; 138.
      - Senator Specter urges AG offer $100,000 reward for info to conviction of bomber of Sharon Rogers' van, November 20, 1989; 139.
      - Senators Specter and Heinz introduce bill to establish satellite federal court in Lancaster, PA, November 21, 1989; 140.
      - Senate passes legislation sponsored by Senator Specter that creates Office of Minority Health within Department of Health and Human Services, November 22, 1989; 141.
      - Senator Specter to meet with veterans groups in Pittsburgh on Monday, November 27, on funding for veterans' health care, November 27, 1989; 142.
      - Senator Specter receives corporate award for showing "fiscal integrity" as a member of the U.S. Senate, December 4, 1989; 143.
      - U.S. Senator Arlen Specter to visit model crack babies treatment program at Pittsburgh area hospital on Monday, December 11, December 8, 1989; 144.
      - University of Pittsburgh awarded $797,977 to continue project studying causes of juvenile delinquency, December 13, 1989; 145.
    - January-June 1990 (Box 1223, Folder 3)
      - Senator Specter, former Governor Scranton, and Steamtown officials to meet with Conrail on Steamtown debt in Philadelphia on Tuesday, January 2, January 2, 1990; 1.
      - U.S. Senator Arlen Specter urges quick cleanup of Monongahela River in Pittsburgh, PA, January 2, 1990; 2.
      - Senator Specter announces that Conrail agrees not to try to collect $1 million debt owed by Steamtown, January 2, 1990; 3.
      - Navy awards multi-million dollar contract for V-22 research and development to Bell Boeing Corporation, January 9, 1990; 4.
      - Monthly cable TV call-in program "Call Senator Specter" becomes "Washington Hotline": U.S. Senator Alan Simpson first guest of new season, January 18, 1990; 5.
      - Senator Specter to discuss issues facing Israel and the Middle East at local synagogue, January 19, 1990; 6.
      - Senator Specter says U.S. Navy, despite any cutbacks, will continue to need the services of the Philadelphia Naval Shipyard, January 25, 1990; 7.
      - Senator Specter asks Defense Secretary Cheney to "make it explicit": no final decision has been made on closure of PNSY in his formal announcement on Monday, January 26, 1990; 8.
      - Senators Specter and Heinz announce federal health assessment for Lackawanna County landfill hazards, January 26, 1990; 9.
      - Senator Specter announces $1,895,000 in federal highway funds for widening of Route 202 in King of Prussia, January 29, 1990; 10.
      - Senator Specter announces Cambria County to get $13.7 million in highway funds for Ebensburg bypass; Beaver County, $666,000 for airport, January 29, 1990; 11.
      - Senator Specter to visit shelter for the homeless in Harrisburg and to address the Lancaster-Lebanon Literacy Council in Lancaster on Monday, February 5, February 5, 1990; 12.
      - Southern Alleghenies region to receive federal funds through the Resource Conservation and Development Program, February 5, 1990; 13.
      - Senator Specter and more than 60 other Senators urge Soviet leader Gorbachev to implement agreement between Aeroflot and El Al Airlines to transport Soviet Jews to Israel, February 6, 1990; 14.
      - All 100 members of the Senate urge Soviet leader Gorbachev to implement agreement between Aeroflot and El Al Airlines to transport Soviet Jews to Israel, February 8, 1990; 15.
      - U.S. Senator Arlen Specter to meet with children infected with the AIDS virus and their parents tomorrow, February 14, at St. Christopher's Hospital for Children in North Philadelphia, February 13, 1990; 16.
      - U.S. Senator Arlen Specter to meet with management and labor on the costs of clean air bill tomorrow at U.S. Steel's Clairton Coke Works in Clairton, February 14, 1990; 17.
      - Senator Specter supports Gateway Mine employees in buy-out plan, February 21, 1990; 18.
      - Resolution by Senator Specter would deny most favored nation status to Soviet Union unless it honors agreement to fly Soviet Jewish emigres directly to Israel, February 28, 1990; 19.
      - Senator Specter receives "Golden Bulldog" award for efforts to cut federal spending, February 28, 1990; 20.
      - EPA Administrator William Reilly to join Senator Specter on "Washington hotline", March 2, 1990; 21.
      - Senator Specter joins member of Congress from the Great Lakes area in pushing legislation to halt the depredations of the Zebra Mussel, March 7, 1990; 22.
      - Senator Specter says Community College of Philadelphia will not have to repay $1,455,682 to U.S. Department of Education for students doing remedial work, March 14, 1990; 23.
      - Senator Specter announces FAA grants to Altoona-Blair County and Westmoreland County airports, March 15, 1990; 24.
      - Senator Specter to join federal and local law enforcement officials at press conference tomorrow to announce BATF anti-drug task force for Philadelphia, March 15, 1990; 25.
      - Senator Specter applauds BATF task force for Philadelphia; says force can make an impact on street crime and drug trafficking using his Armed Career Criminal Act, March 16, 1990; 26.
      - Senator Specter to be in Pittsburgh Monday, March 19, to help Census Bureau highlight its efforts to get an accurate count of area homeless, March 19, 1990; 27.
      - Senators Specter and Heinz to join U.S. Attorney Corbett for press conference on law enforcement in Pittsburgh on Monday, March 26, 1990, 28.
      - Senators Specter and Heinz to join U.S. Attorney Corbett for press conference in Pittsburgh following Corbett's swearing in; Specter asks Corbett to use Career Criminal Bill to attack street crime, March 26, 1990; 29.
      - Senator Specter tells Somerset County commissioners he will push hard for federal funding to complete Route 219 to Maryland border, March 26, 1990; 30.
      - Senator Specter's amendment to clean air bill would provide 20 percent tax credit to power plants that install pollution control technology, March 28, 1990; 31.
      - IRS officials join Senator Arlen Specter to answer viewers questions on "Washington Hotline", April 2, 1990; 32.
      - Senator Specter urges FEMA, NTSB, and Coast Guard to investigate thoroughly weekend oil spill into the Allegheny River, April 3, 1990; 33.
      - Senator Specter announces that Pittsburgh firm wins Small Business Administration's "Prime Contractor of the Year" award, April 17, 1990; 34.
      - Senator Specter announces he will introduce legislation to create 10% tax credit for development of high-speed intercity rail facilities, April 17, 1990; 35.
      - U.S. Senator Arlen Specter's statement on the passing of Erie Mayor Louis Tullio, April 17, 1990; 36.
      - Specter says amendment to the Clean Air Act made Duquesne Light-General Public Utilities agreement and more jobs for Pennsylvania possible, April 19, 1990; 37.
      - Transportation Secretary Samuel Skinner joins Senator Specter to answer viewer questions on "Washington Hotline", April 20, 1990; 38.
      - U.S. Senator Arlen Specter comments on the importance of observing Earth Day, April 20, 1990; 39.
      - Senator Specter introduces resolution to commend neighborhood crime watch groups and to designate August 7, 1990, as "Crime Watch Day", April 20, 1990; 40.
      - Senator Specter urges prompt investigation of derailment in western PA and action on his hazardous material rail transportation bill, April 23, 1990; 41.
      - Senator Specter to receive award from NAMI for his efforts to combat mental illness, April 24, 1990; 42.
      - Clerys to receive award at White House today; PA couple recommended by Senator Specter for their efforts on campus safety, April 25, 1990; 43.
      - Senators Specter and Levin blast administration for removing Japan from list of unfair traders; introduce bill to extend Super 301, April 27, 1990; 44.
      - Senator Specter to be in Pittsburgh tomorrow to study "new directions" employment training program as Federal Job Training Act comes up for revisions, May 2, 1990; 45.
      - U.S. Senator Arlen Specter asks U.S. Justice Department to submit evidence to a federal grand jury in the move case; says there is still time for indictments, May 4, 1990; 46.
      - Senator Specter heartened on V-22's chances by testimony from Marine Corps General at defense subcommittee hearing, May 8, 1990; 47.
      - Senator Specter warns pro sports leagues that they are jeopardizing their anti-trust exemptions in pushing for more and more "pay-per-view" TV, May 9, 1990; 48.
      - Head of Justice's Civil Rights Division to meet in Washington, D.C., tomorrow on MOVE investigation with Senator Specter and Philadelphia clergymen, May 1990; 49.
      - Senator Specter to bring Senator Biden to Philadelphia on Monday, May 14, in effort to win his support for drug court and federal detention center, May 14, 1990; 50.
      - Navy expert tells Senator Specter that the Philadelphia Naval Shipyard is "best prepared and most economical" for SLEP work on U.S. aircraft carriers, May 15, 1990; 51.
      - Senator Specter announces $2.7 million YOU grant for west Philadelphia neighborhood, May 15, 1990; 52.